var words = 
[
    {
        "question": "وَأَخِيهِ",
        "answer": "and his brother",
        "pcklId": "73",
        "rootWordId": 23,
        "tlit": "wa-akhīhi",
        "frequency": "96",
        "surahnum": "70",
        "ayahnum": "12",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " وَصَاحِبَتِهِ وَأَخِيهِ",
        "rootWord": "أ خ و",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَخ",
        "waznEnglish": "brother",
        "waznTlit": "akh",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "إِذَا",
        "answer": "When",
        "pcklId": "338",
        "rootWordId": 27,
        "tlit": "idhā",
        "frequency": "409",
        "surahnum": "70",
        "ayahnum": "20",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " إِذَا مَسَّهُ الشَّرُّ جَزُوعًا",
        "rootWord": "إِذَا",
        "rootWordType": "nominal",
        "wazn": "إِذَا",
        "waznEnglish": "when",
        "waznTlit": "idhā",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Time adverb)"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَإِذَا",
        "answer": "And when",
        "pcklId": "339",
        "rootWordId": 27,
        "tlit": "wa-idhā",
        "frequency": "409",
        "surahnum": "70",
        "ayahnum": "21",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " وَإِذَا مَسَّهُ الْخَيْرُ مَنُوعًا",
        "rootWord": "إِذَا",
        "rootWordType": "nominal",
        "wazn": "إِذَا",
        "waznEnglish": "when",
        "waznTlit": "idhā",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Time adverb)"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْأَرْضِ",
        "answer": "the earth",
        "pcklId": "440",
        "rootWordId": 32,
        "tlit": "l-arḍi",
        "frequency": "461",
        "surahnum": "70",
        "ayahnum": "14",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " وَمَنْ فِي الْأَرْضِ جَمِيعًا ثُمَّ يُنْجِيهِ",
        "rootWord": "أ ر ض",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أ ر ض",
        "waznEnglish": "the Earth, land",
        "waznTlit": "hamza rā ḍād",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "أَلْفَ",
        "answer": "thousand",
        "pcklId": "17",
        "rootWordId": 56,
        "tlit": "alfa",
        "frequency": "22",
        "surahnum": "70",
        "ayahnum": "4",
        "wordnum": "10",
        "arabicAyah": " تَعْرُجُ الْمَلَائِكَةُ وَالرُّوحُ إِلَيْهِ فِي يَوْمٍ كَانَ مِقْدَارُهُ خَمْسِينَ أَلْفَ",
        "rootWord": "أ ل ف",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَلْف",
        "waznEnglish": "thousand",
        "waznTlit": "alf",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "إِلَّا",
        "answer": "Except",
        "pcklId": "644",
        "rootWordId": 58,
        "tlit": "illā",
        "frequency": "663",
        "surahnum": "70",
        "ayahnum": "22",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " إِلَّا الْمُصَلِّينَ",
        "rootWord": "إِلَّا",
        "rootWordType": "particle",
        "wazn": "إِلَّا",
        "waznEnglish": "except",
        "waznTlit": "illā",
        "waznType": "Particle (Exceptive particle)"
    },
    {
        "question": "إِلَّا",
        "answer": "Except",
        "pcklId": "645",
        "rootWordId": 58,
        "tlit": "illā",
        "frequency": "663",
        "surahnum": "70",
        "ayahnum": "30",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " إِلَّا عَلَىٰ أَزْوَاجِهِمْ أَوْ مَا مَلَكَتْ أَيْمَانُهُمْ فَإِنَّهُمْ غَيْرُ مَلُومِينَ",
        "rootWord": "إِلَّا",
        "rootWordType": "particle",
        "wazn": "إِلَّا",
        "waznEnglish": "except",
        "waznTlit": "illā",
        "waznType": "Particle (Exceptive particle)"
    },
    {
        "question": "الَّتِي",
        "answer": "who",
        "pcklId": "1381",
        "rootWordId": 59,
        "tlit": "allatī",
        "frequency": "1464",
        "surahnum": "70",
        "ayahnum": "13",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " وَفَصِيلَتِهِ الَّتِي تُؤْوِيهِ",
        "rootWord": "ٱلَّذِى",
        "rootWordType": "nominal",
        "wazn": "ٱلَّذِى",
        "waznEnglish": "who, which, that",
        "waznTlit": "alladhī",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Relative pronoun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "الَّذِينَ",
        "answer": "Those who",
        "pcklId": "1382",
        "rootWordId": 59,
        "tlit": "alladhīna",
        "frequency": "1464",
        "surahnum": "70",
        "ayahnum": "23",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " الَّذِينَ هُمْ عَلَىٰ صَلَاتِهِمْ دَائِمُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ٱلَّذِى",
        "rootWordType": "nominal",
        "wazn": "ٱلَّذِى",
        "waznEnglish": "who, which, that",
        "waznTlit": "alladhī",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Relative pronoun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَالَّذِينَ",
        "answer": "And those who",
        "pcklId": "1383",
        "rootWordId": 59,
        "tlit": "wa-alladhīna",
        "frequency": "1464",
        "surahnum": "70",
        "ayahnum": "24",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " وَالَّذِينَ فِي أَمْوَالِهِمْ حَقٌّ مَعْلُومٌ",
        "rootWord": "ٱلَّذِى",
        "rootWordType": "nominal",
        "wazn": "ٱلَّذِى",
        "waznEnglish": "who, which, that",
        "waznTlit": "alladhī",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Relative pronoun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَالَّذِينَ",
        "answer": "And those who",
        "pcklId": "1384",
        "rootWordId": 59,
        "tlit": "wa-alladhīna",
        "frequency": "1464",
        "surahnum": "70",
        "ayahnum": "26",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " وَالَّذِينَ يُصَدِّقُونَ بِيَوْمِ الدِّينِ",
        "rootWord": "ٱلَّذِى",
        "rootWordType": "nominal",
        "wazn": "ٱلَّذِى",
        "waznEnglish": "who, which, that",
        "waznTlit": "alladhī",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Relative pronoun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَالَّذِينَ",
        "answer": "And those who",
        "pcklId": "1385",
        "rootWordId": 59,
        "tlit": "wa-alladhīna",
        "frequency": "1464",
        "surahnum": "70",
        "ayahnum": "27",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " وَالَّذِينَ هُمْ مِنْ عَذَابِ رَبِّهِمْ مُشْفِقُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ٱلَّذِى",
        "rootWordType": "nominal",
        "wazn": "ٱلَّذِى",
        "waznEnglish": "who, which, that",
        "waznTlit": "alladhī",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Relative pronoun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَالَّذِينَ",
        "answer": "And those who",
        "pcklId": "1386",
        "rootWordId": 59,
        "tlit": "wa-alladhīna",
        "frequency": "1464",
        "surahnum": "70",
        "ayahnum": "29",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " وَالَّذِينَ هُمْ لِفُرُوجِهِمْ حَافِظُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ٱلَّذِى",
        "rootWordType": "nominal",
        "wazn": "ٱلَّذِى",
        "waznEnglish": "who, which, that",
        "waznTlit": "alladhī",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Relative pronoun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَالَّذِينَ",
        "answer": "And those who",
        "pcklId": "1387",
        "rootWordId": 59,
        "tlit": "wa-alladhīna",
        "frequency": "1464",
        "surahnum": "70",
        "ayahnum": "32",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " وَالَّذِينَ هُمْ لِأَمَانَاتِهِمْ وَعَهْدِهِمْ رَاعُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ٱلَّذِى",
        "rootWordType": "nominal",
        "wazn": "ٱلَّذِى",
        "waznEnglish": "who, which, that",
        "waznTlit": "alladhī",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Relative pronoun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَالَّذِينَ",
        "answer": "And those who",
        "pcklId": "1388",
        "rootWordId": 59,
        "tlit": "wa-alladhīna",
        "frequency": "1464",
        "surahnum": "70",
        "ayahnum": "33",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " وَالَّذِينَ هُمْ بِشَهَادَاتِهِمْ قَائِمُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ٱلَّذِى",
        "rootWordType": "nominal",
        "wazn": "ٱلَّذِى",
        "waznEnglish": "who, which, that",
        "waznTlit": "alladhī",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Relative pronoun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَالَّذِينَ",
        "answer": "And those who",
        "pcklId": "1389",
        "rootWordId": 59,
        "tlit": "wa-alladhīna",
        "frequency": "1464",
        "surahnum": "70",
        "ayahnum": "34",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " وَالَّذِينَ هُمْ عَلَىٰ صَلَاتِهِمْ يُحَافِظُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ٱلَّذِى",
        "rootWordType": "nominal",
        "wazn": "ٱلَّذِى",
        "waznEnglish": "who, which, that",
        "waznTlit": "alladhī",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Relative pronoun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "الَّذِينَ",
        "answer": "those who",
        "pcklId": "1390",
        "rootWordId": 59,
        "tlit": "alladhīna",
        "frequency": "1464",
        "surahnum": "70",
        "ayahnum": "36",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " فَمَالِ الَّذِينَ كَفَرُوا قِبَلَكَ مُهْطِعِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ٱلَّذِى",
        "rootWordType": "nominal",
        "wazn": "ٱلَّذِى",
        "waznEnglish": "who, which, that",
        "waznTlit": "alladhī",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Relative pronoun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "الَّذِي",
        "answer": "which",
        "pcklId": "1391",
        "rootWordId": 59,
        "tlit": "alladhī",
        "frequency": "1464",
        "surahnum": "70",
        "ayahnum": "42",
        "wordnum": "7",
        "arabicAyah": " فَذَرْهُمْ يَخُوضُوا وَيَلْعَبُوا حَتَّىٰ يُلَاقُوا يَوْمَهُمُ الَّذِي يُوعَدُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ٱلَّذِى",
        "rootWordType": "nominal",
        "wazn": "ٱلَّذِى",
        "waznEnglish": "who, which, that",
        "waznTlit": "alladhī",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Relative pronoun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "الَّذِي",
        "answer": "which",
        "pcklId": "1392",
        "rootWordId": 59,
        "tlit": "alladhī",
        "frequency": "1464",
        "surahnum": "70",
        "ayahnum": "44",
        "wordnum": "7",
        "arabicAyah": " ذَٰلِكَ الْيَوْمُ الَّذِي كَانُوا يُوعَدُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ٱلَّذِى",
        "rootWordType": "nominal",
        "wazn": "ٱلَّذِى",
        "waznEnglish": "who, which, that",
        "waznTlit": "alladhī",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Relative pronoun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "اللَّهِ",
        "answer": "Allah",
        "pcklId": "2792",
        "rootWordId": 61,
        "tlit": "l-lahi",
        "frequency": "2851",
        "surahnum": "70",
        "ayahnum": "3",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " مِنَ اللَّهِ ذِي الْمَعَارِجِ",
        "rootWord": "أ ل ه",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ٱللَّه",
        "waznEnglish": "Allah",
        "waznTlit": "allah",
        "waznType": "Proper noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "إِلَيْهِ",
        "answer": "to Him",
        "pcklId": "707",
        "rootWordId": 63,
        "tlit": "ilayhi",
        "frequency": "742",
        "surahnum": "70",
        "ayahnum": "4",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " تَعْرُجُ الْمَلَائِكَةُ وَالرُّوحُ إِلَيْهِ فِي يَوْمٍ كَانَ مِقْدَارُهُ خَمْسِينَ أَلْفَ سَنَةٍ",
        "rootWord": "إِلَىٰ",
        "rootWordType": "preposition",
        "wazn": "إِلَىٰ",
        "waznEnglish": "to, toward, until",
        "waznTlit": "ilā",
        "waznType": "Preposition"
    },
    {
        "question": "إِلَىٰ",
        "answer": "to",
        "pcklId": "708",
        "rootWordId": 63,
        "tlit": "ilā",
        "frequency": "742",
        "surahnum": "70",
        "ayahnum": "43",
        "wordnum": "7",
        "arabicAyah": " يَوْمَ يَخْرُجُونَ مِنَ الْأَجْدَاثِ سِرَاعًا كَأَنَّهُمْ إِلَىٰ نُصُبٍ يُوفِضُونَ",
        "rootWord": "إِلَىٰ",
        "rootWordType": "preposition",
        "wazn": "إِلَىٰ",
        "waznEnglish": "to, toward, until",
        "waznTlit": "ilā",
        "waznType": "Preposition"
    },
    {
        "question": "لِأَمَانَاتِهِمْ",
        "answer": "of their trusts",
        "pcklId": "561",
        "rootWordId": 75,
        "tlit": "li-amānātihim",
        "frequency": "879",
        "surahnum": "70",
        "ayahnum": "32",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " وَالَّذِينَ هُمْ لِأَمَانَاتِهِمْ وَعَهْدِهِمْ رَاعُونَ",
        "rootWord": "أ م ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَمَٰنَٰت",
        "waznEnglish": "you are secure",
        "waznTlit": "amānāt",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "مَأْمُونٍ",
        "answer": "to be felt secure (of) ",
        "pcklId": "603",
        "rootWordId": 75,
        "tlit": "mamūnin",
        "frequency": "879",
        "surahnum": "70",
        "ayahnum": "28",
        "wordnum": "5",
        "arabicAyah": " إِنَّ عَذَابَ رَبِّهِمْ غَيْرُ مَأْمُونٍ",
        "rootWord": "أ م ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مَأْمُون",
        "waznEnglish": "you are secure",
        "waznTlit": "mamūn",
        "waznType": "Passive participle"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْإِنْسَانَ",
        "answer": "the man",
        "pcklId": "70",
        "rootWordId": 78,
        "tlit": "l-insāna",
        "frequency": "97",
        "surahnum": "70",
        "ayahnum": "19",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " إِنَّ الْإِنْسَانَ خُلِقَ هَلُوعًا",
        "rootWord": "أ ن س",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "إِنسَٰن",
        "waznEnglish": "you perceive",
        "waznTlit": "insān",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "تُؤْوِيهِ",
        "answer": "sheltered him",
        "pcklId": "12",
        "rootWordId": 87,
        "tlit": "tu'wīhi",
        "frequency": "36",
        "surahnum": "70",
        "ayahnum": "13",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " وَفَصِيلَتِهِ الَّتِي تُؤْوِيهِ",
        "rootWord": "أ و ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ءَاوَىٰٓ",
        "waznEnglish": "to give shelter",
        "waznTlit": "āwā",
        "waznType": "Verb (form IV)"
    },
    {
        "question": "نُبَدِّلَ",
        "answer": "[We] replace",
        "pcklId": "21",
        "rootWordId": 106,
        "tlit": "nubaddila",
        "frequency": "44",
        "surahnum": "70",
        "ayahnum": "41",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " عَلَىٰ أَنْ نُبَدِّلَ خَيْرًا مِنْهُمْ وَمَا نَحْنُ بِمَسْبُوقِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ب د ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "بَدَّلَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to change",
        "waznTlit": "baddala",
        "waznType": "Verb (form II)"
    },
    {
        "question": "يُبَصَّرُونَهُمْ",
        "answer": "They will be made to see each other",
        "pcklId": "3",
        "rootWordId": 129,
        "tlit": "yubaṣṣarūnahum",
        "frequency": "148",
        "surahnum": "70",
        "ayahnum": "11",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " يُبَصَّرُونَهُمْ يَوَدُّ الْمُجْرِمُ لَوْ يَفْتَدِي مِنْ عَذَابِ يَوْمِئِذٍ",
        "rootWord": "ب ص ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "يُبَصَّرُ",
        "waznEnglish": "to be made to see",
        "waznTlit": "yubaṣṣaru",
        "waznType": "Verb (form II)"
    },
    {
        "question": "أَبْصَارُهُمْ",
        "answer": "their eyesights",
        "pcklId": "78",
        "rootWordId": 129,
        "tlit": "abṣāruhum",
        "frequency": "148",
        "surahnum": "70",
        "ayahnum": "44",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " خَاشِعَةً أَبْصَارُهُمْ تَرْهَقُهُمْ ذِلَّةٌ",
        "rootWord": "ب ص ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "بَصَر",
        "waznEnglish": "I perceived",
        "waznTlit": "baṣar",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "بَعِيدًا",
        "answer": "(as) far off",
        "pcklId": "233",
        "rootWordId": 139,
        "tlit": "baʿīdan",
        "frequency": "235",
        "surahnum": "70",
        "ayahnum": "6",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " إِنَّهُمْ يَرَوْنَهُ بَعِيدًا",
        "rootWord": "ب ع د",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "بَعِيد",
        "waznEnglish": "was long",
        "waznTlit": "baʿīd",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "ابْتَغَىٰ",
        "answer": "seeks",
        "pcklId": "63",
        "rootWordId": 146,
        "tlit": "ib'taghā",
        "frequency": "96",
        "surahnum": "70",
        "ayahnum": "31",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " فَمَنِ ابْتَغَىٰ وَرَاءَ ذَٰلِكَ فَأُولَٰئِكَ هُمُ الْعَادُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ب غ ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ٱبْتَغَىٰ",
        "waznEnglish": "to seek",
        "waznTlit": "ib'taghā",
        "waznType": "Verb (form VIII)"
    },
    {
        "question": "بِبَنِيهِ",
        "answer": "by his children",
        "pcklId": "172",
        "rootWordId": 160,
        "tlit": "bibanīhi",
        "frequency": "184",
        "surahnum": "70",
        "ayahnum": "11",
        "wordnum": "9",
        "arabicAyah": " يَوَدُّ الْمُجْرِمُ لَوْ يَفْتَدِي مِنْ عَذَابِ يَوْمِئِذٍ بِبَنِيهِ",
        "rootWord": "ب ن ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "بُنَىّ",
        "waznEnglish": "they built",
        "waznTlit": "buna",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْجِبَالُ",
        "answer": "the mountains",
        "pcklId": "29",
        "rootWordId": 219,
        "tlit": "l-jibālu",
        "frequency": "41",
        "surahnum": "70",
        "ayahnum": "9",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " وَتَكُونُ الْجِبَالُ كَالْعِهْنِ",
        "rootWord": "ج ب ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "جَبَل",
        "waznEnglish": "hill",
        "waznTlit": "jabal",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْأَجْدَاثِ",
        "answer": "the graves",
        "pcklId": "2",
        "rootWordId": 228,
        "tlit": "l-ajdāthi",
        "frequency": "3",
        "surahnum": "70",
        "ayahnum": "43",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " يَوْمَ يَخْرُجُونَ مِنَ الْأَجْدَاثِ سِرَاعًا كَأَنَّهُمْ إِلَىٰ نُصُبٍ يُوفِضُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ج د ث",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ج د ث",
        "waznEnglish": "the graves",
        "waznTlit": "jīm dāl thā",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْمُجْرِمُ",
        "answer": "the criminal",
        "pcklId": "54",
        "rootWordId": 241,
        "tlit": "l-muj'rimu",
        "frequency": "66",
        "surahnum": "70",
        "ayahnum": "11",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " يَوَدُّ الْمُجْرِمُ لَوْ يَفْتَدِي مِنْ عَذَابِ يَوْمِئِذٍ بِبَنِيهِ",
        "rootWord": "ج ر م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مُجْرِم",
        "waznEnglish": "incite you",
        "waznTlit": "muj'rim",
        "waznType": "Active participle (form IV) (Noun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "جَزُوعًا",
        "answer": "distressed",
        "pcklId": "1",
        "rootWordId": 244,
        "tlit": "jazūʿan",
        "frequency": "2",
        "surahnum": "70",
        "ayahnum": "20",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " إِذَا مَسَّهُ الشَّرُّ جَزُوعًا",
        "rootWord": "ج ز ع",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "جَزُوع",
        "waznEnglish": "whether we show intolerance",
        "waznTlit": "jazūʿ",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَجَمَعَ",
        "answer": "And collected",
        "pcklId": "17",
        "rootWordId": 260,
        "tlit": "wajamaʿa",
        "frequency": "129",
        "surahnum": "70",
        "ayahnum": "18",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " وَجَمَعَ فَأَوْعَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "ج م ع",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "جَمَعَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to gather, to collect",
        "waznTlit": "jamaʿa",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "جَمِيعًا",
        "answer": "all",
        "pcklId": "120",
        "rootWordId": 260,
        "tlit": "jamīʿan",
        "frequency": "129",
        "surahnum": "70",
        "ayahnum": "14",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " وَمَنْ فِي الْأَرْضِ جَمِيعًا ثُمَّ يُنْجِيهِ",
        "rootWord": "ج م ع",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "جَمِيع",
        "waznEnglish": "We will gather them",
        "waznTlit": "jamīʿ",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "جَمِيلًا",
        "answer": "good",
        "pcklId": "9",
        "rootWordId": 261,
        "tlit": "jamīlan",
        "frequency": "11",
        "surahnum": "70",
        "ayahnum": "5",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " فَاصْبِرْ صَبْرًا جَمِيلًا",
        "rootWord": "ج م ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "جَمِيل",
        "waznEnglish": "(is) beauty",
        "waznTlit": "jamīl",
        "waznType": "Adjective"
    },
    {
        "question": "جَنَّاتٍ",
        "answer": "Gardens",
        "pcklId": "120",
        "rootWordId": 267,
        "tlit": "jannātin",
        "frequency": "201",
        "surahnum": "70",
        "ayahnum": "35",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " أُولَٰئِكَ فِي جَنَّاتٍ مُكْرَمُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ج ن ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "جَنَّة",
        "waznEnglish": "covered",
        "waznTlit": "jannat",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "جَنَّةَ",
        "answer": "a Garden",
        "pcklId": "121",
        "rootWordId": 267,
        "tlit": "jannata",
        "frequency": "201",
        "surahnum": "70",
        "ayahnum": "38",
        "wordnum": "7",
        "arabicAyah": " أَيَطْمَعُ كُلُّ امْرِئٍ مِنْهُمْ أَنْ يُدْخَلَ جَنَّةَ نَعِيمٍ",
        "rootWord": "ج ن ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "جَنَّة",
        "waznEnglish": "covered",
        "waznTlit": "jannat",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَالْمَحْرُومِ",
        "answer": "and the deprived",
        "pcklId": "77",
        "rootWordId": 312,
        "tlit": "wal-maḥrūmi",
        "frequency": "83",
        "surahnum": "70",
        "ayahnum": "25",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " لِلسَّائِلِ وَالْمَحْرُومِ",
        "rootWord": "ح ر م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مَحْرُوم",
        "waznEnglish": "He has forbidden",
        "waznTlit": "maḥrūm",
        "waznType": "Passive participle"
    },
    {
        "question": "يُحَافِظُونَ",
        "answer": "keep a guard ",
        "pcklId": "10",
        "rootWordId": 339,
        "tlit": "yuḥāfiẓūna",
        "frequency": "44",
        "surahnum": "70",
        "ayahnum": "34",
        "wordnum": "5",
        "arabicAyah": " وَالَّذِينَ هُمْ عَلَىٰ صَلَاتِهِمْ يُحَافِظُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ح ف ظ",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "يُحَافِظُ",
        "waznEnglish": "to guard",
        "waznTlit": "yuḥāfiẓu",
        "waznType": "Verb (form III)"
    },
    {
        "question": "حَافِظُونَ",
        "answer": "(are) guardians",
        "pcklId": "24",
        "rootWordId": 339,
        "tlit": "ḥāfiẓūna",
        "frequency": "44",
        "surahnum": "70",
        "ayahnum": "29",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " وَالَّذِينَ هُمْ لِفُرُوجِهِمْ حَافِظُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ح ف ظ",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "حَٰفِظ",
        "waznEnglish": "(orders) them to guard",
        "waznTlit": "ḥāfiẓ",
        "waznType": "Active participle"
    },
    {
        "question": "حَقٌّ",
        "answer": "(is) a right",
        "pcklId": "275",
        "rootWordId": 344,
        "tlit": "ḥaqqun",
        "frequency": "287",
        "surahnum": "70",
        "ayahnum": "24",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " وَالَّذِينَ فِي أَمْوَالِهِمْ حَقٌّ مَعْلُومٌ",
        "rootWord": "ح ق ق",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "حَقّ",
        "waznEnglish": "deserved ",
        "waznTlit": "ḥaqq",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "حَمِيمٌ",
        "answer": "a friend",
        "pcklId": "11",
        "rootWordId": 355,
        "tlit": "ḥamīmun",
        "frequency": "21",
        "surahnum": "70",
        "ayahnum": "10",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " وَلَا يَسْأَلُ حَمِيمٌ حَمِيمًا",
        "rootWord": "ح م م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "حَمِيم",
        "waznEnglish": "boiling water",
        "waznTlit": "ḥamīm",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "حَمِيمًا",
        "answer": "(about) a friend",
        "pcklId": "12",
        "rootWordId": 355,
        "tlit": "ḥamīman",
        "frequency": "21",
        "surahnum": "70",
        "ayahnum": "10",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " وَلَا يَسْأَلُ حَمِيمٌ حَمِيمًا",
        "rootWord": "ح م م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "حَمِيم",
        "waznEnglish": "boiling water",
        "waznTlit": "ḥamīm",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "يَخْرُجُونَ",
        "answer": "they will come out",
        "pcklId": "51",
        "rootWordId": 397,
        "tlit": "yakhrujūna",
        "frequency": "182",
        "surahnum": "70",
        "ayahnum": "43",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " يَوْمَ يَخْرُجُونَ مِنَ الْأَجْدَاثِ سِرَاعًا كَأَنَّهُمْ إِلَىٰ نُصُبٍ يُوفِضُونَ",
        "rootWord": "خ ر ج",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "خَرَجَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to go out, to come out, to depart, to leave",
        "waznTlit": "kharaja",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "خَاشِعَةً",
        "answer": "Humbled",
        "pcklId": "14",
        "rootWordId": 409,
        "tlit": "khāshiʿatan",
        "frequency": "17",
        "surahnum": "70",
        "ayahnum": "44",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " خَاشِعَةً أَبْصَارُهُمْ تَرْهَقُهُمْ ذِلَّةٌ ذَٰلِكَ الْيَوْمُ الَّذِي كَانُوا يُوعَدُونَ",
        "rootWord": "خ ش ع",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "خَاشِع",
        "waznEnglish": "And (will be) humbled",
        "waznTlit": "khāshiʿ",
        "waznType": "Active participle"
    },
    {
        "question": "خُلِقَ",
        "answer": "was created",
        "pcklId": "160",
        "rootWordId": 431,
        "tlit": "khuliqa",
        "frequency": "261",
        "surahnum": "70",
        "ayahnum": "19",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " إِنَّ الْإِنْسَانَ خُلِقَ هَلُوعًا",
        "rootWord": "خ ل ق",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "خَلَقَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to create",
        "waznTlit": "khalaqa",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "خَلَقْنَاهُمْ",
        "answer": "[We] have created them",
        "pcklId": "161",
        "rootWordId": 431,
        "tlit": "khalaqnāhum",
        "frequency": "261",
        "surahnum": "70",
        "ayahnum": "39",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " كَلَّا إِنَّا خَلَقْنَاهُمْ مِمَّا يَعْلَمُونَ",
        "rootWord": "خ ل ق",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "خَلَقَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to create",
        "waznTlit": "khalaqa",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "خَمْسِينَ",
        "answer": "(is) fifty",
        "pcklId": "4",
        "rootWordId": 436,
        "tlit": "khamsīna",
        "frequency": "8",
        "surahnum": "70",
        "ayahnum": "4",
        "wordnum": "9",
        "arabicAyah": " تَعْرُجُ الْمَلَائِكَةُ وَالرُّوحُ إِلَيْهِ فِي يَوْمٍ كَانَ مِقْدَارُهُ خَمْسِينَ أَلْفَ سَنَةٍ",
        "rootWord": "خ م س",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "خَمْسِين",
        "waznEnglish": "And the fifth",
        "waznTlit": "khamsīn",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "يَخُوضُوا",
        "answer": "(to) converse vainly",
        "pcklId": "7",
        "rootWordId": 443,
        "tlit": "yakhūḍū",
        "frequency": "12",
        "surahnum": "70",
        "ayahnum": "42",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " فَذَرْهُمْ يَخُوضُوا وَيَلْعَبُوا حَتَّىٰ يُلَاقُوا يَوْمَهُمُ الَّذِي يُوعَدُونَ",
        "rootWord": "خ و ض",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "خَاضُ",
        "waznEnglish": "to engage in idle talk, to converse vainly",
        "waznTlit": "khāḍu",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْخَيْرُ",
        "answer": "the good",
        "pcklId": "144",
        "rootWordId": 449,
        "tlit": "l-khayru",
        "frequency": "196",
        "surahnum": "70",
        "ayahnum": "21",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " وَإِذَا مَسَّهُ الْخَيْرُ مَنُوعًا",
        "rootWord": "خ ي ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "خَيْر",
        "waznEnglish": "they select",
        "waznTlit": "khayr",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "خَيْرًا",
        "answer": "(with) better",
        "pcklId": "145",
        "rootWordId": 449,
        "tlit": "khayran",
        "frequency": "196",
        "surahnum": "70",
        "ayahnum": "41",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " عَلَىٰ أَنْ نُبَدِّلَ خَيْرًا مِنْهُمْ وَمَا نَحْنُ بِمَسْبُوقِينَ",
        "rootWord": "خ ي ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "خَيْر",
        "waznEnglish": "they select",
        "waznTlit": "khayr",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "أَدْبَرَ",
        "answer": "turned his back",
        "pcklId": "4",
        "rootWordId": 455,
        "tlit": "adbara",
        "frequency": "44",
        "surahnum": "70",
        "ayahnum": "17",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " تَدْعُو مَنْ أَدْبَرَ وَتَوَلَّىٰ",
        "rootWord": "د ب ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَدْبَرَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to turn away, to depart",
        "waznTlit": "adbara",
        "waznType": "Verb (form IV)"
    },
    {
        "question": "يُدْخَلَ",
        "answer": "he enters",
        "pcklId": "115",
        "rootWordId": 461,
        "tlit": "yud'khala",
        "frequency": "126",
        "surahnum": "70",
        "ayahnum": "38",
        "wordnum": "6",
        "arabicAyah": " أَيَطْمَعُ كُلُّ امْرِئٍ مِنْهُمْ أَنْ يُدْخَلَ جَنَّةَ نَعِيمٍ",
        "rootWord": "د خ ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أُدْخِلَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to admit",
        "waznTlit": "ud'khila",
        "waznType": "Verb (form IV)"
    },
    {
        "question": "تَدْعُو",
        "answer": "Inviting",
        "pcklId": "160",
        "rootWordId": 474,
        "tlit": "tadʿū",
        "frequency": "212",
        "surahnum": "70",
        "ayahnum": "17",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " تَدْعُو مَنْ أَدْبَرَ وَتَوَلَّىٰ",
        "rootWord": "د ع و",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "دَعَا",
        "waznEnglish": "to call, to invite, to pray",
        "waznTlit": "daʿā",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "دَافِعٌ",
        "answer": "any preventer",
        "pcklId": "9",
        "rootWordId": 476,
        "tlit": "dāfiʿun",
        "frequency": "10",
        "surahnum": "70",
        "ayahnum": "2",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " لِلْكَافِرِينَ لَيْسَ لَهُ دَافِعٌ",
        "rootWord": "د ف ع",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "دَافِع",
        "waznEnglish": "defend",
        "waznTlit": "dāfiʿ",
        "waznType": "Active participle"
    },
    {
        "question": "دَائِمُونَ",
        "answer": "(are) constant",
        "pcklId": "8",
        "rootWordId": 496,
        "tlit": "dāimūna",
        "frequency": "9",
        "surahnum": "70",
        "ayahnum": "23",
        "wordnum": "5",
        "arabicAyah": " الَّذِينَ هُمْ عَلَىٰ صَلَاتِهِمْ دَائِمُونَ",
        "rootWord": "د و م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "دَآئِم",
        "waznEnglish": "you keep constantly",
        "waznTlit": "dāim",
        "waznType": "Active participle"
    },
    {
        "question": "الدِّينِ",
        "answer": "(of) the Judgment",
        "pcklId": "80",
        "rootWordId": 498,
        "tlit": "l-dīni",
        "frequency": "101",
        "surahnum": "70",
        "ayahnum": "26",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " وَالَّذِينَ يُصَدِّقُونَ بِيَوْمِ الدِّينِ",
        "rootWord": "د ي ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "دِين",
        "waznEnglish": "they acknowledge",
        "waznTlit": "dīn",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "ذِلَّةٌ",
        "answer": "humiliation",
        "pcklId": "22",
        "rootWordId": 513,
        "tlit": "dhillatun",
        "frequency": "24",
        "surahnum": "70",
        "ayahnum": "44",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " خَاشِعَةً أَبْصَارُهُمْ تَرْهَقُهُمْ ذِلَّةٌ ذَٰلِكَ الْيَوْمُ الَّذِي كَانُوا يُوعَدُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ذ ل ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ذِلَّة",
        "waznEnglish": "we were humiliated",
        "waznTlit": "dhillat",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "يَرَوْنَهُ",
        "answer": "see it",
        "pcklId": "244",
        "rootWordId": 523,
        "tlit": "yarawnahu",
        "frequency": "328",
        "surahnum": "70",
        "ayahnum": "6",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " إِنَّهُمْ يَرَوْنَهُ بَعِيدًا",
        "rootWord": "ر أ ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "رَءَا",
        "waznEnglish": "to see",
        "waznTlit": "raā",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَنَرَاهُ",
        "answer": "But We see it",
        "pcklId": "245",
        "rootWordId": 523,
        "tlit": "wanarāhu",
        "frequency": "328",
        "surahnum": "70",
        "ayahnum": "7",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " وَنَرَاهُ قَرِيبًا",
        "rootWord": "ر أ ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "رَءَا",
        "waznEnglish": "to see",
        "waznTlit": "raā",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "رَبِّهِمْ",
        "answer": "(of) their Lord",
        "pcklId": "896",
        "rootWordId": 524,
        "tlit": "rabbihim",
        "frequency": "980",
        "surahnum": "70",
        "ayahnum": "27",
        "wordnum": "5",
        "arabicAyah": " وَالَّذِينَ هُمْ مِنْ عَذَابِ رَبِّهِمْ مُشْفِقُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ر ب ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "رَبّ",
        "waznEnglish": "the Lord",
        "waznTlit": "rabb",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "رَبِّهِمْ",
        "answer": "(of) your Lord",
        "pcklId": "897",
        "rootWordId": 524,
        "tlit": "rabbihim",
        "frequency": "980",
        "surahnum": "70",
        "ayahnum": "28",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " إِنَّ عَذَابَ رَبِّهِمْ غَيْرُ مَأْمُونٍ",
        "rootWord": "ر ب ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "رَبّ",
        "waznEnglish": "the Lord",
        "waznTlit": "rabb",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "بِرَبِّ",
        "answer": "by (the) Lord",
        "pcklId": "898",
        "rootWordId": 524,
        "tlit": "birabbi",
        "frequency": "980",
        "surahnum": "70",
        "ayahnum": "40",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " فَلَا أُقْسِمُ بِرَبِّ الْمَشَارِقِ وَالْمَغَارِبِ إِنَّا لَقَادِرُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ر ب ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "رَبّ",
        "waznEnglish": "the Lord",
        "waznTlit": "rabb",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "رَاعُونَ",
        "answer": "(are) observers",
        "pcklId": "8",
        "rootWordId": 565,
        "tlit": "rāʿūna",
        "frequency": "10",
        "surahnum": "70",
        "ayahnum": "32",
        "wordnum": "5",
        "arabicAyah": " وَالَّذِينَ هُمْ لِأَمَانَاتِهِمْ وَعَهْدِهِمْ رَاعُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ر ع ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "رَٰعُون",
        "waznEnglish": "and pasture",
        "waznTlit": "rāʿūn",
        "waznType": "Active participle"
    },
    {
        "question": "تَرْهَقُهُمْ",
        "answer": "will cover them",
        "pcklId": "3",
        "rootWordId": 596,
        "tlit": "tarhaquhum",
        "frequency": "10",
        "surahnum": "70",
        "ayahnum": "44",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " خَاشِعَةً أَبْصَارُهُمْ تَرْهَقُهُمْ ذِلَّةٌ ذَٰلِكَ الْيَوْمُ الَّذِي كَانُوا يُوعَدُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ر ه ق",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "يَرْهَقُ",
        "waznEnglish": "to cover",
        "waznTlit": "yarhaqu",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَالرُّوحُ",
        "answer": "and the Spirit",
        "pcklId": "23",
        "rootWordId": 599,
        "tlit": "wal-rūḥu",
        "frequency": "57",
        "surahnum": "70",
        "ayahnum": "4",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " تَعْرُجُ الْمَلَائِكَةُ وَالرُّوحُ إِلَيْهِ فِي يَوْمٍ كَانَ مِقْدَارُهُ خَمْسِينَ أَلْفَ سَنَةٍ",
        "rootWord": "ر و ح",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "رُوح",
        "waznEnglish": "you bring them in",
        "waznTlit": "rūḥ",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "أَزْوَاجِهِمْ",
        "answer": "their spouses",
        "pcklId": "78",
        "rootWordId": 638,
        "tlit": "azwājihim",
        "frequency": "81",
        "surahnum": "70",
        "ayahnum": "30",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " إِلَّا عَلَىٰ أَزْوَاجِهِمْ أَوْ مَا مَلَكَتْ أَيْمَانُهُمْ فَإِنَّهُمْ غَيْرُ مَلُومِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ز و ج",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "زَوْج",
        "waznEnglish": "We married her to you",
        "waznTlit": "zawj",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "سَأَلَ",
        "answer": "Asked",
        "pcklId": "100",
        "rootWordId": 647,
        "tlit": "sa-ala",
        "frequency": "129",
        "surahnum": "70",
        "ayahnum": "1",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " سَأَلَ سَائِلٌ بِعَذَابٍ وَاقِعٍ",
        "rootWord": "س أ ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "سَأَلَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to ask",
        "waznTlit": "sa-ala",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "يَسْأَلُ",
        "answer": "will ask",
        "pcklId": "101",
        "rootWordId": 647,
        "tlit": "yasalu",
        "frequency": "129",
        "surahnum": "70",
        "ayahnum": "10",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " وَلَا يَسْأَلُ حَمِيمٌ حَمِيمًا",
        "rootWord": "س أ ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "سَأَلَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to ask",
        "waznTlit": "sa-ala",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "سَائِلٌ",
        "answer": "a questioner",
        "pcklId": "121",
        "rootWordId": 647,
        "tlit": "sāilun",
        "frequency": "129",
        "surahnum": "70",
        "ayahnum": "1",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " سَأَلَ سَائِلٌ بِعَذَابٍ وَاقِعٍ",
        "rootWord": "س أ ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "سَآئِل",
        "waznEnglish": "you have asked (for)",
        "waznTlit": "sāil",
        "waznType": "Active participle"
    },
    {
        "question": "لِلسَّائِلِ",
        "answer": "For the one who asks",
        "pcklId": "122",
        "rootWordId": 647,
        "tlit": "lilssāili",
        "frequency": "129",
        "surahnum": "70",
        "ayahnum": "25",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " لِلسَّائِلِ وَالْمَحْرُومِ",
        "rootWord": "س أ ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "سَآئِل",
        "waznEnglish": "you have asked (for)",
        "waznTlit": "sāil",
        "waznType": "Active participle"
    },
    {
        "question": "بِمَسْبُوقِينَ",
        "answer": "(are) to be outrun",
        "pcklId": "36",
        "rootWordId": 655,
        "tlit": "bimasbūqīna",
        "frequency": "37",
        "surahnum": "70",
        "ayahnum": "41",
        "wordnum": "8",
        "arabicAyah": " عَلَىٰ أَنْ نُبَدِّلَ خَيْرًا مِنْهُمْ وَمَا نَحْنُ بِمَسْبُوقِينَ",
        "rootWord": "س ب ق",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مَسْبُوقِين",
        "waznEnglish": "has preceded you",
        "waznTlit": "masbūqīn",
        "waznType": "Passive participle"
    },
    {
        "question": "سِرَاعًا",
        "answer": "rapidly",
        "pcklId": "22",
        "rootWordId": 682,
        "tlit": "sirāʿan",
        "frequency": "23",
        "surahnum": "70",
        "ayahnum": "43",
        "wordnum": "5",
        "arabicAyah": " يَوْمَ يَخْرُجُونَ مِنَ الْأَجْدَاثِ سِرَاعًا",
        "rootWord": "س ر ع",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "سِرَاع",
        "waznEnglish": "and they hasten",
        "waznTlit": "sirāʿ",
        "waznType": "Verbal noun (form III)"
    },
    {
        "question": "السَّمَاءُ",
        "answer": "the sky",
        "pcklId": "339",
        "rootWordId": 726,
        "tlit": "l-samāu",
        "frequency": "381",
        "surahnum": "70",
        "ayahnum": "8",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " يَوْمَ تَكُونُ السَّمَاءُ كَالْمُهْلِ",
        "rootWord": "س م و",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "سَمَآء",
        "waznEnglish": "[I] (have) named her",
        "waznTlit": "samā",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "سَنَةٍ",
        "answer": "year(s)",
        "pcklId": "19",
        "rootWordId": 732,
        "tlit": "sanatin",
        "frequency": "20",
        "surahnum": "70",
        "ayahnum": "4",
        "wordnum": "11",
        "arabicAyah": " تَعْرُجُ الْمَلَائِكَةُ وَالرُّوحُ إِلَيْهِ فِي يَوْمٍ كَانَ مِقْدَارُهُ خَمْسِينَ أَلْفَ سَنَةٍ",
        "rootWord": "س ن و",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "سَنَة",
        "waznEnglish": "(the) flash",
        "waznTlit": "sanat",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "الشَّرُّ",
        "answer": "the evil",
        "pcklId": "19",
        "rootWordId": 767,
        "tlit": "l-sharu",
        "frequency": "31",
        "surahnum": "70",
        "ayahnum": "20",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " إِذَا مَسَّهُ الشَّرُّ جَزُوعًا",
        "rootWord": "ش ر ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "شَرّ",
        "waznEnglish": "(is) bad",
        "waznTlit": "sharr",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْمَشَارِقِ",
        "answer": "(of) the risings",
        "pcklId": "12",
        "rootWordId": 770,
        "tlit": "l-mashāriqi",
        "frequency": "17",
        "surahnum": "70",
        "ayahnum": "40",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " فَلَا أُقْسِمُ بِرَبِّ الْمَشَارِقِ وَالْمَغَارِبِ إِنَّا لَقَادِرُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ش ر ق",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مَشْرِق",
        "waznEnglish": "And (will) shine",
        "waznTlit": "mashriq",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "مُشْفِقُونَ",
        "answer": "(are) fearful ",
        "pcklId": "10",
        "rootWordId": 783,
        "tlit": "mush'fiqūna",
        "frequency": "11",
        "surahnum": "70",
        "ayahnum": "27",
        "wordnum": "6",
        "arabicAyah": " وَالَّذِينَ هُمْ مِنْ عَذَابِ رَبِّهِمْ مُشْفِقُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ش ف ق",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مُشْفِقُون",
        "waznEnglish": "and they feared",
        "waznTlit": "mush'fiqūn",
        "waznType": "Active participle (form IV)"
    },
    {
        "question": "الشِّمَالِ",
        "answer": "the left",
        "pcklId": "11",
        "rootWordId": 798,
        "tlit": "l-shimāli",
        "frequency": "12",
        "surahnum": "70",
        "ayahnum": "37",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " عَنِ الْيَمِينِ وَعَنِ الشِّمَالِ عِزِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ش م ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "شِّمَال",
        "waznEnglish": "contains",
        "waznTlit": "shimāl",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "بِشَهَادَاتِهِمْ",
        "answer": "in their testimonies",
        "pcklId": "55",
        "rootWordId": 801,
        "tlit": "bishahādātihim",
        "frequency": "160",
        "surahnum": "70",
        "ayahnum": "33",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " وَالَّذِينَ هُمْ بِشَهَادَاتِهِمْ قَائِمُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ش ه د",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "شَهَٰدَٰت",
        "waznEnglish": "(were) witnessing",
        "waznTlit": "shahādāt",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "لِلشَّوَىٰ",
        "answer": "of the skin of the head",
        "pcklId": "1",
        "rootWordId": 809,
        "tlit": "lilshawā",
        "frequency": "2",
        "surahnum": "70",
        "ayahnum": "16",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " نَزَّاعَةً لِلشَّوَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "ش و ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "شَّوَىٰ",
        "waznEnglish": "(which) scalds",
        "waznTlit": "shawā",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "فَاصْبِرْ",
        "answer": "So be patient",
        "pcklId": "53",
        "rootWordId": 818,
        "tlit": "fa-iṣ'bir",
        "frequency": "103",
        "surahnum": "70",
        "ayahnum": "5",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " فَاصْبِرْ صَبْرًا جَمِيلًا",
        "rootWord": "ص ب ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "صَبَرَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to be patient",
        "waznTlit": "ṣabara",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "صَبْرًا",
        "answer": "a patience",
        "pcklId": "78",
        "rootWordId": 818,
        "tlit": "ṣabran",
        "frequency": "103",
        "surahnum": "70",
        "ayahnum": "5",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " فَاصْبِرْ صَبْرًا جَمِيلًا",
        "rootWord": "ص ب ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "صَبْر",
        "waznEnglish": "we endure",
        "waznTlit": "ṣabr",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَصَاحِبَتِهِ",
        "answer": "And his spouse",
        "pcklId": "92",
        "rootWordId": 822,
        "tlit": "waṣāḥibatihi",
        "frequency": "97",
        "surahnum": "70",
        "ayahnum": "12",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " وَصَاحِبَتِهِ وَأَخِيهِ",
        "rootWord": "ص ح ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "صَٰحِبَة",
        "waznEnglish": "can be protected",
        "waznTlit": "ṣāḥibat",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "يُصَدِّقُونَ",
        "answer": "accept (the) truth",
        "pcklId": "22",
        "rootWordId": 830,
        "tlit": "yuṣaddiqūna",
        "frequency": "155",
        "surahnum": "70",
        "ayahnum": "26",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " وَالَّذِينَ يُصَدِّقُونَ بِيَوْمِ الدِّينِ",
        "rootWord": "ص د ق",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "صَدَّقَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to accept truth, to admit, to confirm, to believe",
        "waznTlit": "ṣaddaqa",
        "waznType": "Verb (form II)"
    },
    {
        "question": "صَلَاتِهِمْ",
        "answer": "their prayer",
        "pcklId": "90",
        "rootWordId": 857,
        "tlit": "ṣalātihim",
        "frequency": "99",
        "surahnum": "70",
        "ayahnum": "23",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " الَّذِينَ هُمْ عَلَىٰ صَلَاتِهِمْ دَائِمُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ص ل و",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "صَلَوٰة",
        "waznEnglish": "praying",
        "waznTlit": "ṣalat",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "صَلَاتِهِمْ",
        "answer": "their prayer",
        "pcklId": "91",
        "rootWordId": 857,
        "tlit": "ṣalātihim",
        "frequency": "99",
        "surahnum": "70",
        "ayahnum": "34",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " وَالَّذِينَ هُمْ عَلَىٰ صَلَاتِهِمْ يُحَافِظُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ص ل و",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "صَلَوٰة",
        "waznEnglish": "praying",
        "waznTlit": "ṣalat",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْمُصَلِّينَ",
        "answer": "those who pray ",
        "pcklId": "96",
        "rootWordId": 857,
        "tlit": "l-muṣalīna",
        "frequency": "99",
        "surahnum": "70",
        "ayahnum": "22",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " إِلَّا الْمُصَلِّينَ",
        "rootWord": "ص ل و",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مُصَلِّين",
        "waznEnglish": "praying",
        "waznTlit": "muṣallīn",
        "waznType": "Active participle (form II)"
    },
    {
        "question": "أَيَطْمَعُ",
        "answer": "Does long",
        "pcklId": "6",
        "rootWordId": 925,
        "tlit": "ayaṭmaʿu",
        "frequency": "12",
        "surahnum": "70",
        "ayahnum": "38",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " أَيَطْمَعُ كُلُّ امْرِئٍ مِنْهُمْ أَنْ يُدْخَلَ جَنَّةَ نَعِيمٍ",
        "rootWord": "ط م ع",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "يَطْمَعُ",
        "waznEnglish": "to hope, to desire",
        "waznTlit": "yaṭmaʿu",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْعَادُونَ",
        "answer": "(are) the transgressors ",
        "pcklId": "101",
        "rootWordId": 967,
        "tlit": "l-ʿādūna",
        "frequency": "106",
        "surahnum": "70",
        "ayahnum": "31",
        "wordnum": "7",
        "arabicAyah": " فَمَنِ ابْتَغَىٰ وَرَاءَ ذَٰلِكَ فَأُولَٰئِكَ هُمُ الْعَادُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ع د و",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "عَاد",
        "waznEnglish": "transgress",
        "waznTlit": "ʿād",
        "waznType": "Active participle"
    },
    {
        "question": "بِعَذَابٍ",
        "answer": "about a punishment",
        "pcklId": "347",
        "rootWordId": 968,
        "tlit": "biʿadhābin",
        "frequency": "373",
        "surahnum": "70",
        "ayahnum": "1",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " سَأَلَ سَائِلٌ بِعَذَابٍ وَاقِعٍ",
        "rootWord": "ع ذ ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "عَذَاب",
        "waznEnglish": "and He will punish",
        "waznTlit": "ʿadhāb",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "عَذَابِ",
        "answer": "(the) punishment",
        "pcklId": "348",
        "rootWordId": 968,
        "tlit": "ʿadhābi",
        "frequency": "373",
        "surahnum": "70",
        "ayahnum": "11",
        "wordnum": "7",
        "arabicAyah": " يَوَدُّ الْمُجْرِمُ لَوْ يَفْتَدِي مِنْ عَذَابِ يَوْمِئِذٍ بِبَنِيهِ",
        "rootWord": "ع ذ ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "عَذَاب",
        "waznEnglish": "and He will punish",
        "waznTlit": "ʿadhāb",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "عَذَابِ",
        "answer": "(the) punishment",
        "pcklId": "349",
        "rootWordId": 968,
        "tlit": "ʿadhābi",
        "frequency": "373",
        "surahnum": "70",
        "ayahnum": "27",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " وَالَّذِينَ هُمْ مِنْ عَذَابِ رَبِّهِمْ مُشْفِقُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ع ذ ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "عَذَاب",
        "waznEnglish": "and He will punish",
        "waznTlit": "ʿadhāb",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "عَذَابَ",
        "answer": "(the) punishment",
        "pcklId": "350",
        "rootWordId": 968,
        "tlit": "ʿadhāba",
        "frequency": "373",
        "surahnum": "70",
        "ayahnum": "28",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " إِنَّ عَذَابَ رَبِّهِمْ غَيْرُ مَأْمُونٍ",
        "rootWord": "ع ذ ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "عَذَاب",
        "waznEnglish": "and He will punish",
        "waznTlit": "ʿadhāb",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "تَعْرُجُ",
        "answer": "Ascend",
        "pcklId": "4",
        "rootWordId": 971,
        "tlit": "taʿruju",
        "frequency": "9",
        "surahnum": "70",
        "ayahnum": "4",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " تَعْرُجُ الْمَلَائِكَةُ وَالرُّوحُ إِلَيْهِ",
        "rootWord": "ع ر ج",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "يَعْرُجُ",
        "waznEnglish": "to ascend",
        "waznTlit": "yaʿruju",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْمَعَارِجِ",
        "answer": "(of) the ways of ascent",
        "pcklId": "8",
        "rootWordId": 971,
        "tlit": "l-maʿāriji",
        "frequency": "9",
        "surahnum": "70",
        "ayahnum": "3",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " مِنَ اللَّهِ ذِي الْمَعَارِجِ",
        "rootWord": "ع ر ج",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مَعَارِج",
        "waznEnglish": "(to) ascend",
        "waznTlit": "maʿārij",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "عِزِينَ",
        "answer": "(in) separate groups",
        "pcklId": "0",
        "rootWordId": 985,
        "tlit": "ʿizīna",
        "frequency": "1",
        "surahnum": "70",
        "ayahnum": "37",
        "wordnum": "5",
        "arabicAyah": " عَنِ الْيَمِينِ وَعَنِ الشِّمَالِ عِزِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ع ز و",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ع ز و",
        "waznEnglish": "(in) separate groups",
        "waznTlit": "ʿayn zāy wāw",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "يَعْلَمُونَ",
        "answer": "they know",
        "pcklId": "362",
        "rootWordId": 1016,
        "tlit": "yaʿlamūna",
        "frequency": "854",
        "surahnum": "70",
        "ayahnum": "39",
        "wordnum": "5",
        "arabicAyah": " كَلَّا إِنَّا خَلَقْنَاهُمْ مِمَّا يَعْلَمُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ع ل م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "عَلِمَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to know",
        "waznTlit": "ʿalima",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "مَعْلُومٌ",
        "answer": "known",
        "pcklId": "851",
        "rootWordId": 1016,
        "tlit": "maʿlūmun",
        "frequency": "854",
        "surahnum": "70",
        "ayahnum": "24",
        "wordnum": "5",
        "arabicAyah": " وَالَّذِينَ فِي أَمْوَالِهِمْ حَقٌّ مَعْلُومٌ",
        "rootWord": "ع ل م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مَّعْلُوم",
        "waznEnglish": "they know",
        "waznTlit": "maʿlūm",
        "waznType": "Passive participle (Adjective)"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَعَهْدِهِمْ",
        "answer": "and their promise",
        "pcklId": "45",
        "rootWordId": 1032,
        "tlit": "waʿahdihim",
        "frequency": "46",
        "surahnum": "70",
        "ayahnum": "32",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " وَالَّذِينَ هُمْ لِأَمَانَاتِهِمْ وَعَهْدِهِمْ رَاعُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ع ه د",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "عَهْد",
        "waznEnglish": "And We made a covenant",
        "waznTlit": "ʿahd",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "كَالْعِهْنِ",
        "answer": "like wool",
        "pcklId": "0",
        "rootWordId": 1033,
        "tlit": "kal-ʿih'ni",
        "frequency": "2",
        "surahnum": "70",
        "ayahnum": "9",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " وَتَكُونُ الْجِبَالُ كَالْعِهْنِ",
        "rootWord": "ع ه ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ع ه ن",
        "waznEnglish": "like wool",
        "waznTlit": "ʿayn hā nūn",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَالْمَغَارِبِ",
        "answer": "and the settings",
        "pcklId": "17",
        "rootWordId": 1054,
        "tlit": "wal-maghāribi",
        "frequency": "19",
        "surahnum": "70",
        "ayahnum": "40",
        "wordnum": "5",
        "arabicAyah": " فَلَا أُقْسِمُ بِرَبِّ الْمَشَارِقِ وَالْمَغَارِبِ إِنَّا لَقَادِرُونَ",
        "rootWord": "غ ر ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مَغْرِب",
        "waznEnglish": "it set",
        "waznTlit": "maghrib",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "غَيْرُ",
        "answer": "(is) not",
        "pcklId": "145",
        "rootWordId": 1095,
        "tlit": "ghayru",
        "frequency": "154",
        "surahnum": "70",
        "ayahnum": "28",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " إِنَّ عَذَابَ رَبِّهِمْ غَيْرُ مَأْمُونٍ",
        "rootWord": "غ ي ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "غَيْر",
        "waznEnglish": "so they will surely change",
        "waznTlit": "ghayr",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "غَيْرُ",
        "answer": "(are) not",
        "pcklId": "146",
        "rootWordId": 1095,
        "tlit": "ghayru",
        "frequency": "154",
        "surahnum": "70",
        "ayahnum": "30",
        "wordnum": "9",
        "arabicAyah": " إِلَّا عَلَىٰ أَزْوَاجِهِمْ أَوْ مَا مَلَكَتْ أَيْمَانُهُمْ فَإِنَّهُمْ غَيْرُ مَلُومِينَ",
        "rootWord": "غ ي ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "غَيْر",
        "waznEnglish": "so they will surely change",
        "waznTlit": "ghayr",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "يَفْتَدِي",
        "answer": "he (could be) ransomed",
        "pcklId": "8",
        "rootWordId": 1112,
        "tlit": "yaftadī",
        "frequency": "13",
        "surahnum": "70",
        "ayahnum": "11",
        "wordnum": "5",
        "arabicAyah": " يَوَدُّ الْمُجْرِمُ لَوْ يَفْتَدِي مِنْ عَذَابِ يَوْمِئِذٍ بِبَنِيهِ",
        "rootWord": "ف د ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ٱفْتَدَىٰ",
        "waznEnglish": "to offer ransom",
        "waznTlit": "if'tadā",
        "waznType": "Verb (form VIII)"
    },
    {
        "question": "لِفُرُوجِهِمْ",
        "answer": "their modesty",
        "pcklId": "8",
        "rootWordId": 1115,
        "tlit": "lifurūjihim",
        "frequency": "9",
        "surahnum": "70",
        "ayahnum": "29",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " وَالَّذِينَ هُمْ لِفُرُوجِهِمْ حَافِظُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ف ر ج",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "فَرْج",
        "waznEnglish": "is cleft asunder",
        "waznTlit": "farj",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَفَصِيلَتِهِ",
        "answer": "And his nearest kindred",
        "pcklId": "34",
        "rootWordId": 1135,
        "tlit": "wafaṣīlatihi",
        "frequency": "43",
        "surahnum": "70",
        "ayahnum": "13",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " وَفَصِيلَتِهِ الَّتِي تُؤْوِيهِ",
        "rootWord": "ف ص ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "فَصِيلَت",
        "waznEnglish": "set out",
        "waznTlit": "faṣīlat",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "قِبَلَكَ",
        "answer": "before you",
        "pcklId": "275",
        "rootWordId": 1174,
        "tlit": "qibalaka",
        "frequency": "294",
        "surahnum": "70",
        "ayahnum": "36",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " فَمَالِ الَّذِينَ كَفَرُوا قِبَلَكَ مُهْطِعِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ق ب ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "قِبَل",
        "waznEnglish": "will be accepted",
        "waznTlit": "qibal",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Location adverb)"
    },
    {
        "question": "مِقْدَارُهُ",
        "answer": "its measure",
        "pcklId": "107",
        "rootWordId": 1181,
        "tlit": "miq'dāruhu",
        "frequency": "132",
        "surahnum": "70",
        "ayahnum": "4",
        "wordnum": "8",
        "arabicAyah": " فِي يَوْمٍ كَانَ مِقْدَارُهُ خَمْسِينَ أَلْفَ سَنَةٍ",
        "rootWord": "ق د ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مِقْدَار",
        "waznEnglish": "they have control",
        "waznTlit": "miq'dār",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "لَقَادِرُونَ",
        "answer": "(are) surely Able",
        "pcklId": "117",
        "rootWordId": 1181,
        "tlit": "laqādirūna",
        "frequency": "132",
        "surahnum": "70",
        "ayahnum": "40",
        "wordnum": "7",
        "arabicAyah": " فَلَا أُقْسِمُ بِرَبِّ الْمَشَارِقِ وَالْمَغَارِبِ إِنَّا لَقَادِرُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ق د ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "قَادِر",
        "waznEnglish": "they have control",
        "waznTlit": "qādir",
        "waznType": "Active participle"
    },
    {
        "question": "قَرِيبًا",
        "answer": "near",
        "pcklId": "85",
        "rootWordId": 1187,
        "tlit": "qarīban",
        "frequency": "96",
        "surahnum": "70",
        "ayahnum": "7",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " وَنَرَاهُ قَرِيبًا",
        "rootWord": "ق ر ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "قَرِيب",
        "waznEnglish": "[you two] approach",
        "waznTlit": "qarīb",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "أُقْسِمُ",
        "answer": "I swear",
        "pcklId": "17",
        "rootWordId": 1201,
        "tlit": "uq'simu",
        "frequency": "33",
        "surahnum": "70",
        "ayahnum": "40",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " فَلَا أُقْسِمُ بِرَبِّ الْمَشَارِقِ وَالْمَغَارِبِ إِنَّا لَقَادِرُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ق س م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَقْسَمُ",
        "waznEnglish": "to swear",
        "waznTlit": "aqsamu",
        "waznType": "Verb (form IV)"
    },
    {
        "question": "قَائِمُونَ",
        "answer": "stand firm",
        "pcklId": "599",
        "rootWordId": 1246,
        "tlit": "qāimūna",
        "frequency": "660",
        "surahnum": "70",
        "ayahnum": "33",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " وَالَّذِينَ هُمْ بِشَهَادَاتِهِمْ قَائِمُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ق و م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "قَآئِم",
        "waznEnglish": "they stand (still)",
        "waznTlit": "qāim",
        "waznType": "Active participle"
    },
    {
        "question": "مُكْرَمُونَ",
        "answer": "honored",
        "pcklId": "45",
        "rootWordId": 1267,
        "tlit": "muk'ramūna",
        "frequency": "47",
        "surahnum": "70",
        "ayahnum": "35",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " أُولَٰئِكَ فِي جَنَّاتٍ مُكْرَمُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ك ر م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مُّكْرَمُون",
        "waznEnglish": "You have honored",
        "waznTlit": "muk'ramūn",
        "waznType": "Passive participle (form IV) (Noun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "كَفَرُوا",
        "answer": "disbelieve",
        "pcklId": "280",
        "rootWordId": 1280,
        "tlit": "kafarū",
        "frequency": "525",
        "surahnum": "70",
        "ayahnum": "36",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " فَمَالِ الَّذِينَ كَفَرُوا قِبَلَكَ مُهْطِعِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ك ف ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "كَفَرَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to disbelieve",
        "waznTlit": "kafara",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "لِلْكَافِرِينَ",
        "answer": "To the disbelievers",
        "pcklId": "507",
        "rootWordId": 1280,
        "tlit": "lil'kāfirīna",
        "frequency": "525",
        "surahnum": "70",
        "ayahnum": "2",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " لِلْكَافِرِينَ لَيْسَ لَهُ دَافِعٌ",
        "rootWord": "ك ف ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "كَٰفِرُون",
        "waznEnglish": "disbelieve[d]",
        "waznTlit": "kāfirūn",
        "waznType": "Active participle (Noun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "كُلُّ",
        "answer": "every",
        "pcklId": "348",
        "rootWordId": 1288,
        "tlit": "kullu",
        "frequency": "377",
        "surahnum": "70",
        "ayahnum": "38",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " أَيَطْمَعُ كُلُّ امْرِئٍ مِنْهُمْ أَنْ يُدْخَلَ جَنَّةَ نَعِيمٍ",
        "rootWord": "ك ل ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "كُلّ",
        "waznEnglish": "(is) a burden",
        "waznTlit": "kull",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "كَانَ",
        "answer": "[is]",
        "pcklId": "1305",
        "rootWordId": 1305,
        "tlit": "kāna",
        "frequency": "1390",
        "surahnum": "70",
        "ayahnum": "4",
        "wordnum": "7",
        "arabicAyah": " فِي يَوْمٍ كَانَ مِقْدَارُهُ خَمْسِينَ أَلْفَ سَنَةٍ",
        "rootWord": "ك و ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "كَانَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to be",
        "waznTlit": "kāna",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "تَكُونُ",
        "answer": "will be",
        "pcklId": "1306",
        "rootWordId": 1305,
        "tlit": "takūnu",
        "frequency": "1390",
        "surahnum": "70",
        "ayahnum": "8",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " يَوْمَ تَكُونُ السَّمَاءُ كَالْمُهْلِ",
        "rootWord": "ك و ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "كَانَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to be",
        "waznTlit": "kāna",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَتَكُونُ",
        "answer": "And will be",
        "pcklId": "1307",
        "rootWordId": 1305,
        "tlit": "watakūnu",
        "frequency": "1390",
        "surahnum": "70",
        "ayahnum": "9",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " وَتَكُونُ الْجِبَالُ كَالْعِهْنِ",
        "rootWord": "ك و ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "كَانَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to be",
        "waznTlit": "kāna",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "كَانُوا",
        "answer": "they were",
        "pcklId": "1308",
        "rootWordId": 1305,
        "tlit": "kānū",
        "frequency": "1390",
        "surahnum": "70",
        "ayahnum": "44",
        "wordnum": "8",
        "arabicAyah": " ذَٰلِكَ الْيَوْمُ الَّذِي كَانُوا يُوعَدُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ك و ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "كَانَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to be",
        "waznTlit": "kāna",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَيَلْعَبُوا",
        "answer": "and amuse themselves",
        "pcklId": "8",
        "rootWordId": 1333,
        "tlit": "wayalʿabū",
        "frequency": "20",
        "surahnum": "70",
        "ayahnum": "42",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " فَذَرْهُمْ يَخُوضُوا وَيَلْعَبُوا حَتَّىٰ يُلَاقُوا يَوْمَهُمُ الَّذِي يُوعَدُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ل ع ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "يَلْعَبْ",
        "waznEnglish": "to play",
        "waznTlit": "yalʿab",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "يُلَاقُوا",
        "answer": "they meet",
        "pcklId": "22",
        "rootWordId": 1347,
        "tlit": "yulāqū",
        "frequency": "146",
        "surahnum": "70",
        "ayahnum": "42",
        "wordnum": "5",
        "arabicAyah": " فَذَرْهُمْ يَخُوضُوا وَيَلْعَبُوا حَتَّىٰ يُلَاقُوا يَوْمَهُمُ الَّذِي يُوعَدُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ل ق ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "يُلَٰقُ",
        "waznEnglish": "to they meet",
        "waznTlit": "yulāqu",
        "waznType": "Verb (form III)"
    },
    {
        "question": "مَلُومِينَ",
        "answer": "blameworthy",
        "pcklId": "11",
        "rootWordId": 1359,
        "tlit": "malūmīna",
        "frequency": "14",
        "surahnum": "70",
        "ayahnum": "30",
        "wordnum": "10",
        "arabicAyah": " إِلَّا عَلَىٰ أَزْوَاجِهِمْ أَوْ مَا مَلَكَتْ أَيْمَانُهُمْ فَإِنَّهُمْ غَيْرُ مَلُومِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ل و م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مَلُوم",
        "waznEnglish": "you blamed me",
        "waznTlit": "malūm",
        "waznType": "Passive participle"
    },
    {
        "question": "لَيْسَ",
        "answer": "not",
        "pcklId": "84",
        "rootWordId": 1363,
        "tlit": "laysa",
        "frequency": "89",
        "surahnum": "70",
        "ayahnum": "2",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " لِلْكَافِرِينَ لَيْسَ لَهُ دَافِعٌ",
        "rootWord": "ل ي س",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ل ي س",
        "waznEnglish": "to not be",
        "waznTlit": "lām yā sīn",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "امْرِئٍ",
        "answer": "person",
        "pcklId": "30",
        "rootWordId": 1381,
        "tlit": "im'ri-in",
        "frequency": "38",
        "surahnum": "70",
        "ayahnum": "38",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " أَيَطْمَعُ كُلُّ امْرِئٍ مِنْهُمْ أَنْ يُدْخَلَ جَنَّةَ نَعِيمٍ",
        "rootWord": "م ر أ",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ٱمْرِئ",
        "waznEnglish": "an evil man",
        "waznTlit": "im'ri",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "مَسَّهُ",
        "answer": "touches him",
        "pcklId": "54",
        "rootWordId": 1394,
        "tlit": "massahu",
        "frequency": "61",
        "surahnum": "70",
        "ayahnum": "20",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " إِذَا مَسَّهُ الشَّرُّ جَزُوعًا",
        "rootWord": "م س س",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مَسَّ",
        "waznEnglish": "to touch",
        "waznTlit": "massa",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "مَسَّهُ",
        "answer": "touches him",
        "pcklId": "55",
        "rootWordId": 1394,
        "tlit": "massahu",
        "frequency": "61",
        "surahnum": "70",
        "ayahnum": "21",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " وَإِذَا مَسَّهُ الْخَيْرُ مَنُوعًا",
        "rootWord": "م س س",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مَسَّ",
        "waznEnglish": "to touch",
        "waznTlit": "massa",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "مَلَكَتْ",
        "answer": "they possess",
        "pcklId": "40",
        "rootWordId": 1415,
        "tlit": "malakat",
        "frequency": "206",
        "surahnum": "70",
        "ayahnum": "30",
        "wordnum": "6",
        "arabicAyah": " إِلَّا عَلَىٰ أَزْوَاجِهِمْ أَوْ مَا مَلَكَتْ أَيْمَانُهُمْ فَإِنَّهُمْ غَيْرُ مَلُومِينَ",
        "rootWord": "م ل ك",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مَلَكَتْ",
        "waznEnglish": "to possess, to have power",
        "waznTlit": "malakat",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْمَلَائِكَةُ",
        "answer": "the Angels",
        "pcklId": "144",
        "rootWordId": 1415,
        "tlit": "l-malāikatu",
        "frequency": "206",
        "surahnum": "70",
        "ayahnum": "4",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " تَعْرُجُ الْمَلَائِكَةُ وَالرُّوحُ إِلَيْهِ فِي يَوْمٍ كَانَ مِقْدَارُهُ خَمْسِينَ أَلْفَ سَنَةٍ",
        "rootWord": "م ل ك",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مَلَك",
        "waznEnglish": "possesses",
        "waznTlit": "malak",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "مَنُوعًا",
        "answer": "withholding",
        "pcklId": "14",
        "rootWordId": 1418,
        "tlit": "manūʿan",
        "frequency": "17",
        "surahnum": "70",
        "ayahnum": "21",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " وَإِذَا مَسَّهُ الْخَيْرُ مَنُوعًا",
        "rootWord": "م ن ع",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مَنُوع",
        "waznEnglish": "prevents",
        "waznTlit": "manūʿ",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "كَالْمُهْلِ",
        "answer": "like molten copper",
        "pcklId": "5",
        "rootWordId": 1422,
        "tlit": "kal-muh'li",
        "frequency": "6",
        "surahnum": "70",
        "ayahnum": "8",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " يَوْمَ تَكُونُ السَّمَاءُ كَالْمُهْلِ",
        "rootWord": "م ه ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مُهْل",
        "waznEnglish": "and allow them respite ",
        "waznTlit": "muh'l",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "أَمْوَالِهِمْ",
        "answer": "their wealth",
        "pcklId": "75",
        "rootWordId": 1427,
        "tlit": "amwālihim",
        "frequency": "86",
        "surahnum": "70",
        "ayahnum": "24",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " وَالَّذِينَ فِي أَمْوَالِهِمْ حَقٌّ مَعْلُومٌ",
        "rootWord": "م و ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "م و ل",
        "waznEnglish": "[the] wealth",
        "waznTlit": "mīm wāw lām",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "يُنْجِيهِ",
        "answer": "it (could) save him",
        "pcklId": "62",
        "rootWordId": 1445,
        "tlit": "yunjīhi",
        "frequency": "84",
        "surahnum": "70",
        "ayahnum": "14",
        "wordnum": "6",
        "arabicAyah": " وَمَنْ فِي الْأَرْضِ جَمِيعًا ثُمَّ يُنْجِيهِ",
        "rootWord": "ن ج و",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَنجَىٰ",
        "waznEnglish": "to save",
        "waznTlit": "anjā",
        "waznType": "Verb (form IV)"
    },
    {
        "question": "نَزَّاعَةً",
        "answer": "A remover",
        "pcklId": "18",
        "rootWordId": 1457,
        "tlit": "nazzāʿatan",
        "frequency": "20",
        "surahnum": "70",
        "ayahnum": "16",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " نَزَّاعَةً لِلشَّوَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "ن ز ع",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "نَزَّاعَة",
        "waznEnglish": "and You take away",
        "waznTlit": "nazzāʿat",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "نُصُبٍ",
        "answer": "a goal",
        "pcklId": "9",
        "rootWordId": 1474,
        "tlit": "nuṣubin",
        "frequency": "32",
        "surahnum": "70",
        "ayahnum": "43",
        "wordnum": "8",
        "arabicAyah": " كَأَنَّهُمْ إِلَىٰ نُصُبٍ يُوفِضُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ن ص ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "نُصُب",
        "waznEnglish": "they are fixed",
        "waznTlit": "nuṣub",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "نَعِيمٍ",
        "answer": "(of) Delight",
        "pcklId": "133",
        "rootWordId": 1492,
        "tlit": "naʿīmin",
        "frequency": "140",
        "surahnum": "70",
        "ayahnum": "38",
        "wordnum": "8",
        "arabicAyah": " أَيَطْمَعُ كُلُّ امْرِئٍ مِنْهُمْ أَنْ يُدْخَلَ جَنَّةَ نَعِيمٍ",
        "rootWord": "ن ع م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "نَعِيم",
        "waznEnglish": "then good",
        "waznTlit": "naʿīm",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "مُهْطِعِينَ",
        "answer": "(they) hasten",
        "pcklId": "2",
        "rootWordId": 1557,
        "tlit": "muh'ṭiʿīna",
        "frequency": "3",
        "surahnum": "70",
        "ayahnum": "36",
        "wordnum": "5",
        "arabicAyah": " فَمَالِ الَّذِينَ كَفَرُوا قِبَلَكَ مُهْطِعِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ه ط ع",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ه ط ع",
        "waznEnglish": "Racing ahead",
        "waznTlit": "hā ṭā ʿayn",
        "waznType": "Active participle (form IV)"
    },
    {
        "question": "هَلُوعًا",
        "answer": "anxious ",
        "pcklId": "0",
        "rootWordId": 1558,
        "tlit": "halūʿan",
        "frequency": "1",
        "surahnum": "70",
        "ayahnum": "19",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " إِنَّ الْإِنْسَانَ خُلِقَ هَلُوعًا",
        "rootWord": "ه ل ع",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ه ل ع",
        "waznEnglish": "anxious ",
        "waznTlit": "hā lām ʿayn",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "يَوَدُّ",
        "answer": "Would wish",
        "pcklId": "16",
        "rootWordId": 1596,
        "tlit": "yawaddu",
        "frequency": "29",
        "surahnum": "70",
        "ayahnum": "11",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " يَوَدُّ الْمُجْرِمُ لَوْ يَفْتَدِي مِنْ عَذَابِ يَوْمِئِذٍ بِبَنِيهِ",
        "rootWord": "و د د",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "وَدَّ",
        "waznEnglish": "to love, to wish",
        "waznTlit": "wadda",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "فَذَرْهُمْ",
        "answer": "So leave them",
        "pcklId": "35",
        "rootWordId": 1600,
        "tlit": "fadharhum",
        "frequency": "45",
        "surahnum": "70",
        "ayahnum": "42",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " فَذَرْهُمْ يَخُوضُوا وَيَلْعَبُوا حَتَّىٰ يُلَاقُوا يَوْمَهُمُ الَّذِي يُوعَدُونَ",
        "rootWord": "و ذ ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "و ذ ر",
        "waznEnglish": "to leave, to forsake",
        "waznTlit": "wāw dhāl rā",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَرَاءَ",
        "answer": "beyond",
        "pcklId": "16",
        "rootWordId": 1604,
        "tlit": "warāa",
        "frequency": "32",
        "surahnum": "70",
        "ayahnum": "31",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " فَمَنِ ابْتَغَىٰ وَرَاءَ ذَٰلِكَ فَأُولَٰئِكَ هُمُ الْعَادُونَ",
        "rootWord": "و ر ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "وَرَآء",
        "waznEnglish": "to hide",
        "waznTlit": "warā",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Location adverb)"
    },
    {
        "question": "يُوعَدُونَ",
        "answer": "they are promised",
        "pcklId": "65",
        "rootWordId": 1626,
        "tlit": "yūʿadūna",
        "frequency": "151",
        "surahnum": "70",
        "ayahnum": "42",
        "wordnum": "8",
        "arabicAyah": " فَذَرْهُمْ يَخُوضُوا وَيَلْعَبُوا حَتَّىٰ يُلَاقُوا يَوْمَهُمُ الَّذِي يُوعَدُونَ",
        "rootWord": "و ع د",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "وَعَدَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to promise",
        "waznTlit": "waʿada",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "يُوعَدُونَ",
        "answer": "promised",
        "pcklId": "66",
        "rootWordId": 1626,
        "tlit": "yūʿadūna",
        "frequency": "151",
        "surahnum": "70",
        "ayahnum": "44",
        "wordnum": "9",
        "arabicAyah": " تَرْهَقُهُمْ ذِلَّةٌ ذَٰلِكَ الْيَوْمُ الَّذِي كَانُوا يُوعَدُونَ",
        "rootWord": "و ع د",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "وَعَدَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to promise",
        "waznTlit": "waʿada",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "فَأَوْعَىٰ",
        "answer": "and hoarded",
        "pcklId": "1",
        "rootWordId": 1628,
        "tlit": "fa-awʿā",
        "frequency": "7",
        "surahnum": "70",
        "ayahnum": "18",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " وَجَمَعَ فَأَوْعَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "و ع ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَوْعَىٰٓ",
        "waznEnglish": "to hoard, to keep",
        "waznTlit": "awʿā",
        "waznType": "Verb (form IV)"
    },
    {
        "question": "يُوفِضُونَ",
        "answer": "hastening",
        "pcklId": "0",
        "rootWordId": 1631,
        "tlit": "yūfiḍūna",
        "frequency": "1",
        "surahnum": "70",
        "ayahnum": "43",
        "wordnum": "9",
        "arabicAyah": " كَأَنَّهُمْ إِلَىٰ نُصُبٍ يُوفِضُونَ",
        "rootWord": "و ف ض",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "و ف ض",
        "waznEnglish": "to hasten",
        "waznTlit": "wāw fā ḍād",
        "waznType": "Verb (form IV)"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَاقِعٍ",
        "answer": "bound to happen",
        "pcklId": "20",
        "rootWordId": 1639,
        "tlit": "wāqiʿin",
        "frequency": "24",
        "surahnum": "70",
        "ayahnum": "1",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " سَأَلَ سَائِلٌ بِعَذَابٍ وَاقِعٍ",
        "rootWord": "و ق ع",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "وَاقِع",
        "waznEnglish": "(became) incumbent",
        "waznTlit": "wāqiʿ",
        "waznType": "Active participle (Adjective)"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَتَوَلَّىٰ",
        "answer": "and went away",
        "pcklId": "103",
        "rootWordId": 1648,
        "tlit": "watawallā",
        "frequency": "232",
        "surahnum": "70",
        "ayahnum": "17",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " تَدْعُو مَنْ أَدْبَرَ وَتَوَلَّىٰ",
        "rootWord": "و ل ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "تَوَلَّىٰ",
        "waznEnglish": "to turn",
        "waznTlit": "tawallā",
        "waznType": "Verb (form V)"
    },
    {
        "question": "أَيْمَانُهُمْ",
        "answer": "rightfully",
        "pcklId": "67",
        "rootWordId": 1662,
        "tlit": "aymānuhum",
        "frequency": "71",
        "surahnum": "70",
        "ayahnum": "30",
        "wordnum": "7",
        "arabicAyah": " إِلَّا عَلَىٰ أَزْوَاجِهِمْ أَوْ مَا مَلَكَتْ أَيْمَانُهُمْ فَإِنَّهُمْ غَيْرُ مَلُومِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ي م ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "يَمِين",
        "waznEnglish": "the right",
        "waznTlit": "yamīn",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْيَمِينِ",
        "answer": "the right",
        "pcklId": "68",
        "rootWordId": 1662,
        "tlit": "l-yamīni",
        "frequency": "71",
        "surahnum": "70",
        "ayahnum": "37",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " عَنِ الْيَمِينِ وَعَنِ الشِّمَالِ عِزِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ي م ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "يَمِين",
        "waznEnglish": "the right",
        "waznTlit": "yamīn",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "يَوْمٍ",
        "answer": "a Day",
        "pcklId": "296",
        "rootWordId": 1664,
        "tlit": "yawmin",
        "frequency": "405",
        "surahnum": "70",
        "ayahnum": "4",
        "wordnum": "6",
        "arabicAyah": " تَعْرُجُ الْمَلَائِكَةُ وَالرُّوحُ إِلَيْهِ فِي يَوْمٍ كَانَ مِقْدَارُهُ خَمْسِينَ أَلْفَ سَنَةٍ",
        "rootWord": "ي و م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ي و م",
        "waznEnglish": "(of the) Day",
        "waznTlit": "yā wāw mīm",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "بِيَوْمِ",
        "answer": "(of the) Day",
        "pcklId": "297",
        "rootWordId": 1664,
        "tlit": "biyawmi",
        "frequency": "405",
        "surahnum": "70",
        "ayahnum": "26",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " وَالَّذِينَ يُصَدِّقُونَ بِيَوْمِ الدِّينِ",
        "rootWord": "ي و م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ي و م",
        "waznEnglish": "(of the) Day",
        "waznTlit": "yā wāw mīm",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "يَوْمَهُمُ",
        "answer": "their Day",
        "pcklId": "298",
        "rootWordId": 1664,
        "tlit": "yawmahumu",
        "frequency": "405",
        "surahnum": "70",
        "ayahnum": "42",
        "wordnum": "6",
        "arabicAyah": " فَذَرْهُمْ يَخُوضُوا وَيَلْعَبُوا حَتَّىٰ يُلَاقُوا يَوْمَهُمُ الَّذِي يُوعَدُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ي و م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ي و م",
        "waznEnglish": "(of the) Day",
        "waznTlit": "yā wāw mīm",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "يَوْمَ",
        "answer": "(The) Day",
        "pcklId": "299",
        "rootWordId": 1664,
        "tlit": "yawma",
        "frequency": "405",
        "surahnum": "70",
        "ayahnum": "43",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " يَوْمَ يَخْرُجُونَ مِنَ الْأَجْدَاثِ سِرَاعًا",
        "rootWord": "ي و م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ي و م",
        "waznEnglish": "(of the) Day",
        "waznTlit": "yā wāw mīm",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْيَوْمُ",
        "answer": "(is) the Day",
        "pcklId": "300",
        "rootWordId": 1664,
        "tlit": "l-yawmu",
        "frequency": "405",
        "surahnum": "70",
        "ayahnum": "44",
        "wordnum": "6",
        "arabicAyah": " ذَٰلِكَ الْيَوْمُ الَّذِي كَانُوا يُوعَدُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ي و م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ي و م",
        "waznEnglish": "(of the) Day",
        "waznTlit": "yā wāw mīm",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "يَوْمَ",
        "answer": "(The) Day ",
        "pcklId": "392",
        "rootWordId": 1664,
        "tlit": "yawma",
        "frequency": "405",
        "surahnum": "70",
        "ayahnum": "8",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " يَوْمَ تَكُونُ السَّمَاءُ كَالْمُهْلِ",
        "rootWord": "ي و م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ي و م",
        "waznEnglish": "(of the) Day",
        "waznTlit": "yā wāw mīm",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Time adverb)"
    }
]; 
export default words;